Guide to the Hudson Shore Labor School Documents 1947-1955
Hudson Shore Labor School Documents
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Hudson Shore Labor School Documents, 1947-1955
5597
Hudson Shore Labor School; Hill, James C.
0.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Consists primarily of memoranda and reports concerning the school's establishment and curricula in workers' education.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Founded in 1939 as the Bryn Mawr College Summer School for Women Workers in Industry, the Hudson Shore Labor School (HSLS) moved to its West Park, N.Y. location in 1949, expanding into an institute for training and development for workers and unionists.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documents consist of memoranda and notes pertaining to workshops, training, budgets, curricula, faculty, labor history and workers' education; minutes and agenda of meetings of the faculty and Board of Trustees (1949-1951); annual reports of the Board of Trustees; reports and statements of the Rutgers Institute of Management and Industrial Relations regarding the curricula and programs offered at the HSLS; and faculty evaluations of training programs (1948-1951).
Also correspondence of L.H. Kerrison (Rutgers Institute of Management and Industrial Relations, faculty) with Helen D. Lockwood (HSLS trustee) on transferring HSLS workers' education sessions to Rutgers and of James C. Hill (Sarah Lawrence College, faculty) with Hilda W. Smith (HSLS trustee) on meetings and curricula. Additionally, press releases, bulletins, financial statements and pamphlets generated by and pertaining to the school's programs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hill, James C., 1914-; Kerrison, Irvine L. H. (Irvine Ledward Hamilton), 1916-; Lockwood, Helen D.; Smith, Hilda (Hilda Worthington); Hudson Shore Labor School; Rutgers University. Institute of Management and Industrial Relations
Subjects:
Adult education teachers -- Training of -- United States.; Adult education.; Adult eduction teachers.; Workers' education. New Jersey. Curricula.; Workers' education. United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Records (documents)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
RELATED MATERIALS
Related Collections:
5703: James C. Hill Additional Files
CONTAINER LIST
- Minutes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Financial Data (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Publications, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Publications, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Publications, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous-Board of Trustees Info; Faculty & Student Lists (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous-Session Info; Training Programs, Releases, Reports (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous-Evaluations & Questionnaires; Info of Hudson Shore School (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous-Photos, Notes, Songs, etc. (Box 1, Folder 14)